Guide to the Henry Hurford Janes-Josephine Baker Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal Papers, 1926-86; Series II; 1; (3 boxes)
  - BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS
    - Research Notes
      - Josephine Baker England tour, 1945 Apr-May (Box 4, Folder 184)
      - Josephine Baker miscellaneous, 1943-76 (Box 4, Folder 185)
      - "Josephine Baker (one day visit to London 29th August) (Box 4, Folder 186)
      - Josephine Baker's stage appearances and writings (Box 4, Folder 187)
      - Library reference notes, [1975?] (Box 4, Folder 188)
      - "Life of Josephine Baker: Notes for Margaret", 1975 Aug 29 (Box 4, Folder 189)
      - List of Josephine Baker's adopted children, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 190)
      - List of research materials about and letters from Josephine Baker, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 191)
      - Meeting with Margarette Wallace, 1975 Sep 8 (Box 4, Folder 192)
      - Nice diary, 1971 Feb-Mar (Box 4, Folder 193)
      - Questions for Josephine Baker, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 194)
      - Rainbow Tribe, 1970-75, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 195)
      - "Report on the Visit of Marianne Bouillon (17), Stellina Bouillon (9)...", 1973 Jul (Box 4, Folder 196)
      - Souvenir of Josephine Baker - Playing Card, 1969 Jul 8 (Box 4, Folder 197)
      - "Visit to Dennis Van Thal", 1975 May 1 (Box 4, Folder 198)
      - Visit to Monte Carlo, 1970 Jul-Aug (Box 4, Folder 199)
      - "Visit to the Dordogne, S.W. France and Monte Carlo, Monaco", 1967 Aug-Sep (Box 4, Folder 200)
      - "Visit to Villa Dordogne", 1972 Sep 14 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - Newspaper Clippings
      - Aznavour, Charles, 1975 Oct 2 (Box 4, Folder 202)
      - Baker, Jean-Claude, 1976, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 202)
      - Baker, Josephine
        - With Akio Bouillon, 1969 Aug 4 (Box 4, Folder 203)
        - l'Amicale Joséphine Baker, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 203)
        - Biographical sketches, 1976 Apr (Box 4, Folder 204)
        - Biography projects, 1975-81 (Box 4, Folder 204)
        - Book review: Josephine, 1978 Jun 29 (Box 4, Folder 205)
        - Entombment, 1975 Oct 3
          See also: Oversize, Box 7, folder 281
        - Estate sale, 1976 Mar (Box 4, Folder 206)
        - With Les Forces françaises libres, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 206)
        - As Godmother of the Olympic Majorettes, 1974 Dec 26 (Box 4, Folder 207)
        - Hairstyles
          See: Oversize, Box 7, folder 282
        - Human rights concerns, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 207)
          See also: Oversize, Box 7, folder 282
        - Illness
          See: Oversize, Box 7, folder 283
        - Interview, 1974 Nov 21 (Box 4, Folder 208)
          See also: Oversize, Box 7, folder 284
        - With Lionel Hampton, 1971 Mar (Box 4, Folder 208)
        - March for De Gaulle, [1964?] (Box 4, Folder 209)
        - Memorial medallion
          See: Oversize, Box 7, folder 284
        - Les Milandes, 1968
          See also: Oversize, Box 7, folder 285
        - Miscellaneous allusions to Josephine Baker, 1946-72, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 210)
        - Move to Roquebrune-Cap-Martin, 1969 Sep (Box 4, Folder 211)
        - Obituaries, 1975 Apr (Box 4, Folder 212)
          See also: Oversize, Box 7, folder 286
        - Performance reviews
          - Bal D'or, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 213)
          - Cambridge theatre, London, 1945 May 24 (Box 4, Folder 213)
          - Gala de la Croix-Rouge Monegasque, 1969 Sep 11 (Box 4, Folder 213)
            See also: Oversize, Box 7, folder 287
          - London Palladium, 1974 Aug 20 (Box 4, Folder 214)
          - Royal Variety Performance, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 215)
          - With Jo Bouillon, 1945 Sep 28 (Box 4, Folder 216)
        - Relationship with Bob Brady, 1973 Oct 22 (Box 4, Folder 217)
        - Remembrance by Ann Ensor
          See: Oversize, Box 7, folder 288
        - Remembrance by Marcel Sauvage, 1975 Apr 13 (Box 4, Folder 217)
        - Return to Paris
        - "The Story of Popular Music"
          See: Oversize, Box 7, folder 289
        - Visits to England, 1945-67 (Box 4, Folder 218)
        - "Zou-Zou", 1969 Aug 7 (Box 4, Folder 219)
      - Bouillon, Luis, 1975 Aug 12 (Box 4, Folder 220)
      - Evans, Edith, Dame
        See: Oversize, Box 7, folder 290
      - French films, 1976 Jun 6 (Box 4, Folder 221)
      - Legge, Walter, 1980 Mar 29 (Box 4, Folder 222)
      - Miscellaneous subjects, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 223)
        See also: Oversize, Box 7, folder 291
  - PRINTED MATERIAL
    - Advertisements
      - Château de Mercuès, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 224)
      - Scaife, C.H.O.: Tones and Overtones Selected Poems 1926-76, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 225)
      - "Venez aux Milandes", 1960 (Box 5, Folder 226)
    - Baker, Joséphine and Jo Bouillon: Joséphine, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 227)
    - Catalog: Sotheby & Co., 1973 Nov 16 (Box 5, Folder 228)
    - ENSA Record, 1943-44 (Box 5, Folder 229)
    - Flyers
      - Gala Variety Concert with Josephine Baker at Cambridge Theatre, London, 1945 May 14 (Box 5, Folder 230)
      - Josephine Baker at Don Juan at Casanova Club, London, 1953 May (Box 5, Folder 231)
      - Musée National Message Biblique Marc Chagall, Nice, France, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 232)
    - Invitations
      - Josephine Baker Concert, Cambridge Theatre, London, 1945 May 14 (Box 5, Folder 233)
      - Wedding of Luis Bouilon and Michèle de Beukelaer, 1975 Mar 31 (Box 5, Folder 234)
    - Magazines
      - Jours de France
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 292
      - Paris Match
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 293
      - Radio Times
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 294
      - Le Soir Illustré
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 295
    - Map: Paris Metro, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 235)
    - Memorial Service: Cecil Malone, 1986 Nov 14 (Box 5, Folder 236)
    - Menu: Gala Dinner and Dance at Ciro's, 1945 Apr 29 (Box 5, Folder 237)
    - Posters
      - Grand Variety Concert with Josephine Baker, Cambridge Theater, London
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 296
      - Personal Appearance Josephine Baker... for N.A.A.F.I. [1945]
        See: JWJ Broadside drawer
      - Variety Concert with Josephine Baker, London [1945 May]
    - Price List: Denby Repros Ltd.: annotated, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 238)
    - "The Principality of Monaco", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 239)
    - Product labels, 1975, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 240)
    - Programs
      - "The Christmas Story" Church of St. Paul, Monte Carlo, Monaco, 1977 Dec 11 (Box 5, Folder 241)
      - Josephine Baker dans Paris Mes Amours, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 242)
      - Joséphine Baker; Jo Bouillon et son orchestre, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 243)
      - Joséphine Baker 50 ans de Music-Hall/Hommage à Joséphine Baker, Bobino, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 244)
      - Miss Josephine Baker, London Palladium, 1974 Aug (Box 5, Folder 245)
      - Palace of Varieties, Leas Cliff Hall, Folkestone [England], 1977 Apr 27 (Box 5, Folder 246)
      - St. Mary's Convent School Distribution of Prizes, 1974 Dec 13 (Box 5, Folder 247)
    - St. Mary's Convent School: miscellaneous, 1974-75 (Box 5, Folder 248)
    - Song: "Zion's Children", 1935 (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Baker, Josephine
      - With Basil Dean, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 250)
      - Cairo, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 251)
      - Card set: 26 different poses, with container, [1926?] (Box 5, Folder 252)
      - Caricature
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 297
      - Funeral, 1975 Oct 2 (Box 5, Folder 253)
      - "Gala de la Croix Rouge Monegasque"
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 298
      - With Henry Hurford Janes, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 254)
      - In Lace, framed, autographed
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 299
      - With Lars Sorenson, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 255)
      - In Military costume
        See: Oversize, Box 8, folder 300
      - In Ostrich Feathers, [1926?] (Box 5, Folder 256)
      - With Princess Grace, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 257)
      - With Rainbow Tribe, 1959-69 (Box 5, Folder 258)
      - Standing pose
      - Standing pose, autographed and performing for troops in Cairo, 1943, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 259)
      - In Top hat, [1930?] (Box 5, Folder 260)
      - In Turban, [1974?] (Box 5, Folder 261)
    - Bouillon, Akio, 1967, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 262)
    - Grace, Princess of Monaco, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 263)
    - Janes, Henry Hurford, 1954, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 264)
    - Les Milandes (Box 5, Folder 265)
    - Wallace, Margarette, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 266)
  - RELATED PAPERS
    - Bouillon, Stellina
      - Bills and receipts, 1974, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 267)
      - Miscellaneous, 1973-75 (Box 6, Folder 268)
    - Janes, Henry Hurford
      - Addresses notes, 1945-46, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 269)
      - Bills and receipts, 1943-76, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 270)
      - Membership card: Association of Friends of the French Volunteers, 1946 May 3 (Box 6, Folder 271)
      - Notes, 1945-76, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 272)
      - Poem: "In the Tube," photocopy, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 273)
      - Play, untitled, one page, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 274)
      - Telephone messages, 1945-75, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 275)
    - McEnery, Reginald, 1967-71 (Box 6, Folder 276)
    - Wallace, Margarette
      - Business card, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 277)
- Oversize, 1941-78; 3.75; (2 boxes)
  Boxes 7 and 8 hold Oversize material from Series I and II and is arranged in original series order.
  - Correspondence
    - Bouillon, Jo, 1975 Aug (Box 7, Folder 278)
    - Vincent, Adza, 1972 Jul 17 (Box 7, Folder 279)
  - Personal Papers
    - Research Notes
      - ENSA and Josephine Baker (Box 7, Folder 280)
    - Newspaper Clippings
      - Baker, Josephine
        - Entombment, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 281)
        - Hairstyles, 1976 Jul 27 (Box 7, Folder 282)
        - Human rights concerns, 1967-68, n.d.
        - Illness, 1975 Apr 12 (Box 7, Folder 283)
        - Interview, 1974 Aug 26 (Box 7, Folder 284)
        - Memorial medallion, 1976 Apr 11 (Box 7, Folder 284)
        - Les Milandes, 1964, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 285)
        - Obituaries, 1975 Apr (Box 7, Folder 286)
        - Performance review: Gala de la Croix Rouge Monegasque, 1969, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 287)
        - Relationship with Bob Brady, [1969?] (Box 7, Folder 287)
        - Remembrance by Ann Ensor, 1978 Feb 9 (Box 7, Folder 288)
        - Return to Paris, 1948 Feb 21 (Box 7, Folder 288)
        - In "The Story of Popular Music", 1977 Feb 13 (Box 7, Folder 289)
      - Evans, Edith, Dame, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 290)
      - Miscellaneous subjects, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 291)
    - Printed Material
      - Jours de France, 1975 Apr 28 (Box 8, Folder 292)
      - Paris Match, 1975 Apr 26 (Box 8, Folder 293)
      - Radio Times, 1948 Jun 27 (Box 8, Folder 294)
      - Le Soir Illustré, 1975 Apr 17 (Box 8, Folder 295)
      - Grand Variety Concert with Josephine Baker, Cambridge Theater, London, 1945 May 14 (Box 8, Folder 296)
    - Photographs
      - Caricature, print and negative, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 297)
      - "Gala de la Croix Rouge Monegasque" prints and negatives, 1969 Aug 8 (Box 8, Folder 298)
      - In Lace, framed and autographed, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 299)
      - In Military costume, inscribed to Harry Janes, and standing pose, negative, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 300)